你在拍吗
Are you getting this?
我在拍
I'm getting the shot.
但我搞不懂你在做什么
I'm just not getting what you're trying to do.
我们可是在澳大利亚  地球的底端啊
We're in Australia -- it's on the bottom of the globe,
所以除了我  所有人都是上下颠倒的
so everyone here but me is upside-down.
地理知识
It's geography.
现在正好可以告诉你
It's a good time to tell you --
卢克一岁时  我把他头朝下掉地上了
I dropped Luke on his head when he was 1.
好吧  我也来
Okay, I'm up.
你也把他掉地上了吗
Did you drop him, too?
帮我拉下腿  伙计
Grab my leg, buddy.
走着
Here we go.
我来自"下面"那片土地
I come from the land down under.
他不是的
He doesn't.
我父母在澳洲度蜜月时怀上我的
I was conceived in Australia on my parents' honeymoon.
那是个浪漫的仲夏之夜  是那边的夏天
It was a romantic summer night -- their summer --
在公园里的一条毯子上
on a blanket in the park.
我现在还留着那条毯子
I still have that blanket.
菲尔的妈妈留给我们一笔钱去那里旅游
Phil's mom left us money for a trip there,
家里其他人知道后
and when the rest of the family found out,
都要跟着一起来
they all just jumped on board.
我妈的外公是澳大利亚人
My mom's grandfather was Australian,
她每年夏天
and she'd spend her summers
也就是那里的冬天  都会去看望他
-- their winters -- visiting him.
对她而言那是个特别的地方
It was a very special place for her.
她一直希望我去看看
She always wanted me to see it.
等等  你还留着那条毯子吗
Wait -- you still have that blanket?
是啊  傻瓜  就是我们床上那条
Yeah, silly. It's the one on our bed.
你确定不要来点维吉麦酱吗  歌洛莉亚
You sure you don't want some of this vegemite, Gloria?
你会错过美味的
You don't know what you're missing.
不知道里面有什么我是不会吃的
Ay, I don't eat anything unless I know what's in it.
我看过这女人狼吞虎咽地吃猪鼻子
I've seen this woman scarf down a pig's nose.
有时候  人得穿过大半个地球
Sometimes, one must travel halfway across the globe
才能看清家的模样
to get the clearest view of home.
一路上都这样
This was my whole flight.
她在说什么
What's she talking about?
我的大学申请论文
My college-application essay.
他们喜欢成熟有阅历的学生
They want students who are worldly.
你何不写我们的夏威夷之行呢
Oh, why don't you write about our trip to Hawaii
你还直接捧着椰子喝呢
when you drank straight from a coconut?
我觉得哈佛会收到很多
I feel like Harvard's gonna get
那样的论文  所以
a lot of those, so...
各位  我要感激有幸成为
Hey, guys, I just wanted to say thanks
这场庄严的澳大利亚朝拜之行的一员
for being a part of this pilgrimage to majestic Australia,
这里曾是罪犯的流放地
which was once a penal colony.
成熟一点
Grow up.
这里对我妈妈真的很特别
This place was really special to my mom.
她其实给我留了一张
She actually left me a list of things
她觉得我们该做的事情清单
that she thought we should do --
去大堡礁游玩
Visit the great Barrier Reef,
去看丛林
See the bush...
真要这样吗
Really?
还有爬悉尼海港大桥
...and climb the Sydney Harbour Bridge.
你们觉得怎么样  伙伴们
what do you say, mates?
抱歉  亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey,
但你也知道我有恐高症的
but you know how I am with heights.
所以你才从不穿高跟鞋吗
Ah. Is that why you never wear high heels?
你们都愿意一起来的吧
You guys are with me, right?
-当然不  -不  我才不去
- Absolutely not. - Nah, I'm not doing that.
-真的吗  -不去
- Really? - No.
不必担心
No worries.
这句是澳大利亚英语
That's Australian.
我...有必要的话我自己来
I'll, uh, I'll do that one on my own if I have to.
我只是很激动我们能一起来这里
I'm just so excited we're all here together.
-其实我们得走了  -对啊  所以
- Actually, we have to go. - Yeah, so...
以前我们认识个来自澳大利亚的家伙
Back in the day, we knew this guy from Australia.
-是新西兰  -都一样啦
- New Zealand. - Same thing.
他没什么朋友  于是我们很同情他
He didn't have a lot of friends, and we felt sorry for him,
但其实他有点惹人烦
but the truth is, he was kind of annoying.
他总是很兴奋地说个不停
He was one of those guys that was always on.
后来他的签证过期  让我们松了口气
Big relief when his visa ran out.
总之  我并没有错
Anyway, through no fault of my own --
等等  不  等等
Wait, no, wait --
你在Facebook上发布说
you announced on Facebook
我们要去澳大利亚  而他就住在那里
that we were going to Australia, which is where he lives.
费格斯邀请我们吃午饭  我无法拒绝
Fergus invited us to lunch. I couldn't say no.
换我就会拒绝
I could have said no.
所以你的Facebook只有12个好友
Which is why you have 12 friends on Facebook.
克莱尔  亲爱的  我得告诉你
Claire, honey, I got to tell you,
汉诺威那单生意你真的干得太漂亮了
you really knocked it out of the park on the Hanover deal.
拜托  老爸  都是你的功劳啦
Oh, come on, dad. That was all you.
不  是你的功劳
No, it was you.
不  是你啦
No, it was you!
是你  是你的宝贝项目
It was you. It was your baby.
一路上都这样
This was my whole flight.
克莱尔第一次在公司带头做项目
Claire took the lead on her first project at the company
干得很漂亮
and scored a big one.
最棒的是  她打败了那个来自
Best part is, she beat out that arrogant gasbag Earl Norton
橱柜橱柜橱柜橱柜公司的傲慢话唠厄尔
over at Closets, Closets, Closets, Closets.
我真希望我能看到
I wish I could see the look
他那张蠢脸上的表情表情表情表情
on his stupid face, face, face, face.
先干什么呢
So, what's first?
我想曼尼想去歌剧院
I think Manny wants to see the Opera House.
坐了那么长时间的飞机
Actually, it was a long flight.
我想我们要不去邦戴海滩上走走好了
I was thinking maybe just... Hang out on Bondi beach.
好主意  曼尼
That's a great idea, Manny.
邦戴海滩上都是光着上身的美女
Bondi beach is topless.
感谢到到网的介绍
Thank you, TripAdvisor.
那就去海滩吧
Beach it is.
开始我们的澳洲派对吧
Let's get this Aussie party started!
天啊  你的嘴怎么了
Oh, my god. What's wrong with your mouth?
你的嘴唇好厚
Ay! Your lips are huge!
我觉得你是对维吉麦酱过敏了
I think you're allergic to the ve-he-mi-te.
别担心
No worries.
我会有点担心的
I'd be a little worried.
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
■
翻译：亲爱的小饭  冰蓝  小花豆  王大可  慕秋雪  丁小七
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
家  庭
摩  登
第五季 第二十集
[西班牙语]
我妈说乔很好
My mom said that Joe is fine,
他吃了睡  睡醒了起来又继续吃
he ate, he slept, he woke up, and then he ate again.
真是乔的一贯作风
Classic Joe.
卢克和我要去躲躲太阳
So, uh, Luke and I are gonna take a break from the sun.
是啊  我们有点累了[受够了]
Yeah. We're kind of tired.
受够了没看见咪咪
Tired of not seeing boobs.
看着当地人从土地中获得食物
Watching the natives take nourishment from their land
让我清楚地认识到
has made me acutely aware of the fact
我现在只是在叽里呱啦而已
that I am just saying words now.
我到底怎么了
What is wrong with me?
完全没思路[被挡住]
I'm totally blocked.
我也是  过去点
So am I. Scooch.
你好吗
How's it going?
你怎么这么冷淡
Why weren't you all over that?
他帅呆了
He's totally gorgeous.
这个国家的第一大出口商品就是冲浪帅哥
This country's number-one export is hot surfers.
我才不要和第一个看见的人去玩
I'm not gonna buy the first one I see.
我要挑一挑
I'm still browsing.
瞧  袋鼠  我要买一只
Ooh! Kangaroos! I'm going to buy one.
莉莉  我刚才怎么说的
Lily, what did I just say?
我不知道  可能和鞋子有关吧
I don't know. Something about shoes, probably?
你爸爸只给了你买一件纪念品的钱
Your dad gave you enough money for one souvenir.
不要买你第一个看到的东西
Don't buy the first thing you see.
不然整个旅程你都会后悔的
You'll regret it your whole trip.
你说得对
You're right.
我已经够后悔了
I have enough regret.
这不是真的吧
You got to be kidding me.
有人出价比我们低
We got outbid!
什么  是谁
What? By whom?
我让你猜四次
I'll give you four guesses.
该死
Damn it.
等等
Wait a second.
他们给我们48小时来提交新报价
They're giving us 48 hours to submit a new bid.
我们能做到
We can do that.
我们绝对能做到
We can totally do that.
我们回酒店去做新报价
Let's go back to the hotel and figure it out.
不能等等嘛
Can it wait?
是啊  我们在度假呢
Yeah, we're on vacation.
抱歉  各位  我们必须要去
Oh, sorry, guys. We have to do this.
这是我的宝贝项目
This is my baby.
杰
Jay.
-爸爸  -克莱尔
- Dad! - Claire.
歌洛莉亚
Gloria.
好吧  你俩回去工作
Fine! You two go back to work.
菲尔和我要去海里
Phil and I, we're going to walk to the ocean,
没了你们  我们会玩得更开心
and we're going to have more fun without you.
是的
Yeah, we will.
不  不会  完全不会
No, we won't. Not at all.
你们为什么要那样说
Why would you guys even say that?
坐在那儿40分钟后
So, after sitting there for 40 minutes,
我告诉女服务员
I tell the waitress,
我其实很赶时间
"I'm actually in a hurry.
有没有可能在鸡蛋孵出小鸡前
Any chance of getting the eggs
给我上鸡蛋啊
before they turn into chickens?"
她简直是个饭桶
You know? And she's a total bogan.
她说  我要应付五桌客人呢
She's like, "I've got five tables!"
知道他们是怎么送托盘的吗
You know how they have the tray?
她这样舞步滑动
She's sashaying with the legs.
华夫饼是谁的
"Oh, who's got the waffles?!
Who-- who's got the waffles?!"
好了  我们明白  我们明白
All right, we get it. We get it.
人们在看呢
People are looking.
我没法阻止人们看我
Oh, nothing I can do to stop that.
我能想到一个办法
Well, I can think of one thing.
-费格斯  跟你聊天真愉快  -是啊
- Well, listen, Fergus, it has been great catching up, - Yes.
但我们今天得和家人一起度过
but we really have to spend some time with our family today.
打扰了  安德森先生
I'm -- I'm so sorry. Um, Mr. Anderson?
我们是铁杆粉
We are huge fans.
能和您合影吗
Could we get a picture?
当然可以  来吧
Of course. Come on.
过来
Bring it in.
坐在这里  就这样
Sit down there. There you go.
我不会起来的
I won't get up.
怎么回事
What's happening?
我不知道  查查他
I don't know. Google him.
我没有国际流量包
I didn't spring for an international data plan.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你喜欢吗  好吧
You like that? All right.
天啊
Oh, my god!
记得以前你们楼下
Hey, remember your old downstairs neighbor
可以把整个拳头塞进嘴里的邻居吗
that could put his entire fist in his mouth?
小卡
Cam.
我觉得我的拳头变大了
I think my fist got bigger.
费格斯・安德森
等等  费格斯
Wait. Fergus,
你有自己的节目吗
you have your own show?
是啊  只是个小小的脱口秀啦
Yeah. It's just a little talk show.
不算什么
No big deal.
我想在这里算件大事吧
It's a big deal here, I suppose,
是啊
but yeah.
真可惜你们这就要走了
It's a shame you guys have got to leave so soon.
那什么
Oh, well, you know,
我们可以再待一会儿
we could stay for a little bit longer.
-是啊  是啊  -没关系
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - That's fine.
你还没说完那个女服务员的事呢
You never finished the story about the waitress and the...
没错  那个...
Yeah, with the...
谁点的华夫饼
"Who had the waffles?!"
-华夫饼  -华夫饼
- Waffles?! - Waffles?!
克莱尔和杰错过了
I just feel bad that Claire and Jay
这个绝美的国家  同时也是一块大陆的
are missing such a beautiful day in this gorgeous country,
美妙一天真是太不幸了
which is also a continent.
你知道的可真多
You have a lot of facts.
我觉得你的这次精神之旅真是太赞了
I think this spiritual journey of yours is a wonderful thing.
这会让你离你母亲更近一点
I think it's gonna make you feel closer to your mother.
希望如此吧
I hope so.
我很想她
I miss her.
这就是我来这儿的主要原因  亲近母亲
It's the biggest reason I came here -- to connect.
很怪吗
Is that weird?
一点都不
Not at all.
我就经常跟我已故的外婆沟通
I talk to my late grandmother all the time.
她会喜欢这个地方的
She would have loved this place.
或许她现在就在我的身边
I wonder if she's here with me now.
不会  她讨厌坐飞机
No, she doesn't like to fly.
我的父母在同一片海滩上留下了
Isn't it wild that my mom and dad made footprints
爱情的足迹真是...
in this very sa-- aah!
怎么了
What?!
有东西在咬我
Something bit me!
水母
Jellyfish!
搞什么
What is this?
一个露乳的女人都没有
Not one topless woman.
淡定点
Calm down.
你会把咪咪吓跑的
You're gonna spook the boobs.
等等  两点钟方向
Uh, wait -- 2:00.
卢克
Hey, Luke!
卢克  水有多深
Luke! How deep is it?!
别乱吼  显得我们跟白痴似的
Be cool! We don't want to look like idiots!
我的泳裤被冲走了
I lost my bathing suit!
曼尼  帮我找到它
Manny, help me find it!
我没带鼻塞
I don't have my nose plug!
小男孩  你还好吗
Little boy, are you okay?
曼尼  说句话啊
Manny, say something!
小姐  小姐  他的泳裤被冲走了
Miss! Miss! He lost his bathing suit!
宝贝  我来帮你找  没事的
Oh, honey, I can help you find it. It's okay.
我很好
I'm fine!
水很清的
The water's really clear.
我爱死你的豪车了
I love your limo!
你不觉得这有点儿高调吗
You don't think it draws too much attention to me?
说什么鬼话呢
What are you talking abo-o-o-o-o-ut?!
才没有
No.
最后我们跟费格斯在一起
We ended up spending a little more time with Fergus
又多待了一会儿
than we planned.
说实话  这给我们上了一课
Which, honestly, felt like growth to us,
-没错  -因为我觉得
- Yes. - Because I think
有时我们还没了解别人就乱下定论
sometimes we judge people before we get to know them.
难以相信他们竟然让你进来
I cannot believe they let us in here.
你到底有多出名
How famous are you?
有时我觉得我才是供人观赏的动物
Well, sometimes, I feel like I'm the one in the zoo.
我跟这考拉唯一的区别
Only difference between me and this guy
就是我不会尿在你身上
is I won't pee on you.
对吧
Right?
说真的  它们会尿在你身上
Seriously, they will pee on you.
真的吗  它会尿在我们身上
Oh, for real? He will pee on us?
-好吧  -真的吗
- Okay. - Is that so?
结果发现  我们有很多共同点
Turns out, we have a lot in common.
比如我们都不喜欢排队
For example, we all hate standing in lines.
记得把照片发我一份噢
Make sure I get copies of those.
他是不是很幽默
Isn't he funny?
我们跟他是一起的  所以我们就先
We're with him, so we're just gonna...
快来  你们先进
Come on. Through you go.
对不住  费格斯总是这样
Sorry. Classic Fergus,
带我们直接进来
getting us in like this.
小卡
Cam.
下一家礼品店在哪里
Where's the next gift shop?
继续逛礼品店我会疯的  莉莉
I cannot look at another souvenir, Lily.
都是因为你
You did this.
莉莉  放轻松
Lily, relax.
你会找到完美的纪念品的
You'll find the perfect one.
我也想相信你
I want to believe you,
但刚才那个救生员真的是帅到爆棚
but that lifeguard was the cutest boy I've ever seen.
我知道
I know.
你们好
Hey, guys!
在商务中心找到了他们
Found 'em in the business center.
快点走  我们还要赶去丛林的车呢
Come on. We got to catch the bus to the bush.
你们什么时候醒来的
What time did you wake up?
凌晨五点  克莱尔的职业道德感很强
5:00 A.M. Claire has an incredible work ethic.
[Yung-mi人名音似young me]
她跟我年轻时一模一样
She's like a young me.
杨蜜是我们来自韩国的会计
Yung-mi was our accountant from Korea.
操劳过度而死
Died at her desk.
好了  别再谈工作了
Okay, enough work.
-该享受我们的假期了  -没错
- It's time to enjoy our vacation. - Yeah.
知道了  我们只需再弄一下...
Yeah, we just got to finish up a few quick, little thi--
不行  工作结束
No, you're done.
-好吧  不工作了  -我们走吧
- Done. We're done. - Let's go.
杰  我很想你
Jay, I miss you.
而且我一人已经保护不了菲尔了
And besides, I don't know that I can keep Phil safe anymore.
我觉得他会死在这里
I think he's going to die here.
是费格斯的短信
Oh, it's Fergus.
什么  他为什么只给你发短信
What? Why did he text you and not me?
他邀请我们去休・杰克曼的游艇派对
He invited us to a party today on Hugh Jackman's yacht.
什么  今天吗  不要啊
What?! Not today! No!
我想见休・杰克曼
I want to meet Hugh Jackman!
我也是  我也是
I do, too. I do, too.
但我们不能再放家人的鸽子了
But, you know, w-we can't bail on my family again.
这样我们就真的成脑残粉了
That makes us complete star you-know-what-ers.
再说了  小卡  这也会很有意思的
Plus, Cam, this will be fun, too.
每个人都带了防晒霜和防虫剂吧
Everybody have their sunscreen and bug spray?
我带了蛇咬伤急救包
I got the snakebite kit.
各位  我们有个坏消息
Hey, guys, we just got some really bad news.
是啊  所以
Yeah, so...
行走于澳大利亚人祖先曾走过的小径
Walking the paths once trod by the first Australians
让我变得  怎样呢
has made me...what?
难以忍受
Unbearable?
幸运的话
Now, if we're lucky,
我们会见到一些著名的澳大利亚本地物种
we'll see some of Australia's more famous indigenous species --
袋鼠  澳洲野狗  考拉
kangaroo, dingoes, koala.
问个问题
Quick question.
很好  又一个问题
Oh, good -- another one.
那些小袋鼠  或者说幼兽出生的时候
Isn't it true that baby kangaroos, or -- or joeys,
真的没有后腿吗
are born without hind legs?
是的
Yes.
你又一次正确回答了自己的问题
Once again, you've correctly answered your own question.
刚收到橱柜橱柜橱柜公司的厄尔的短信
I just got a text from earl at Closets, Closets, Closets --
我知道那公司叫什么  老爸
I know what it's called, dad.
听听  "祝你下次好运  哈哈"
Listen to this -- "Better luck next time. Ha ha."
他总是知道说什么来激怒我
He always knows what to say to get my goat.
我在等木材供应商给我报价
I'm waiting for a quote from the lumber supplier,
可这次徒步要3个小时  手机会没信号
but this hike is three hours -- I'm gonna lose signal.
我们回去吧
Let's go back.
老爸  我们必须找个靠谱的借口
Dad, we can't just up and leave without a plausible reason wh--
克莱尔受伤了
Claire's hurt!
怎么了
What happened?
你知道她总是笨手笨脚的
Well, you know what a klutz she is.
亲爱的  你还好吧
Honey, are you okay?
不太好
Not really.
我来带她回营地吧
Yeah, well, I -- let me get her back to camp.
我们只会拖慢你们的速度
We're just gonna slow you down.
-来吧  乖女儿   -你们玩得开心
- Come on, sweetheart. -Yeah, you guys have fun.
他们是觉得我们有多白痴
How dumb do they think we are?
有时克莱尔会留给我食物的图片
Sometimes, claire leaves me pictures of food
而不是文字的购物清单
instead of a shopping list.
我好紧张
I'm so nervous.
我们真能看到穿泳装的休・杰克曼吗
Are we gonna see Hugh Jackman in a bathing suit?
我们要对穿泳装的休・杰克曼说什么呢
What do we say to hugh jackman in a bathing suit?
天啊  好"大"
Oh, my god. It's so big.
太直接了吧  不过他说不定会很开心
That's a bit direct, but, you know, he might be flattered.
原来你是在说那艘船
Oh, you're talking about the boat.
费格斯
Fergus!
感谢上帝你们来了
Oh, guys. Thank god you're here.
我刚刚和休大吵了一架
Just had the worst fight with Hugh.
不是吧  怎么了
Oh, no. What happened?
我取笑《悲惨世界》里的罗素・克洛来着
I took a shot at Russell Crowe in "Les Mis."
结果休生气了
Hugh took offense.
他应该知道那角色
Oh, well, he has to know
-不该让罗素来演吧  -他必须知道
- Russell was horribly miscast. - He has to know.
绝对是选角失误
Horribly miscasted.
-不是他的错  -不是他的错
- It's not his fault. - It's not his fault.
他表演得还行  但是...
He was -- the acting was fine, but --
我们上船去把事情说清楚
Okay, let's get on this boat and fix this.
对  把一切说清楚
Yep. Fix it.Come on.
不是这条船
That's not the boat.
他们已经走了
They've already gone.
休穿着条暴露的泳裤站在甲板上
Hugh was standing on his deck in a skimpy, little bathing suit,
看起来很失望
disappointed look on his face.
慢着  我没听错吧  暴露的泳裤吗
Wait. I'm s-- wait. Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Skimpy?
不好意思  站在他的什么上
I'm sorry -- standing on his what?
他的甲板上
On his deck.
[澳洲口音deck和dick"老二"发音相似]
船上的甲板  了解
Of the boat. Got it. Okay.
知道吗
You know what?
我们不需要他们
We don't need them.
我去雇条船  我们可以自己开派对
I'll hire a boat. We'll have our own party!
这才是生活  是吧
This is the life, eh, boys?
所以我们不是开这个去坐大船吗
Oh, s-- so we're not taking this to a bigger boat?
一条大船
A bigger boat!
来块鲜肉派吧
Have a meat pie.
不了  谢谢  不要
No, thank you. No.
不用  谢谢
No, thanks.
你还好吧  菲尔
Are you okay, Phil?
我没事
Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
我只是希望克莱尔能在这里
I just wish Claire was here to see all this.
而且我的脚已经肿成两倍大了
Plus, my foot's twice its normal size,
蚊子还追着我被水母咬过的地方叮
and the mosquitoes are really going after my jellyfish bites.
看哪  一个征兆
Look! A sign!
什么
What?
你想看袋鼠  现在就看到了
You wanted to see a kangaroo, and now you see one.
我想这是你妈妈在告诉你
I think this is your mother trying to tell you
接下来旅途会变得很棒  菲尔
that the rest of the trip is going to be magical, Phil.
我妈就是这种人
That is so my mom,
用袋鼠来传递讯息
to say it with a kangaroo.
看
Look.
太美了
So beautiful.
小心点  你会吓着它的
Okay, but be careful. You're gonna scare him.
亲  你好
G'day, mate.
你会不会...
Hey, aren't you gor--
这个
This one.
不  这个
No, this one!
我快喘不过气了
I can't breathe!
跟莉莉一起买东西绝对是最好的避孕措施
Shopping with Lily is the best birth control in the world.
没错
Yeah.
但你知道这没有实际效果的吧
But you know it's not, right?
这个
Ooh! This one!
感谢上帝  快点买吧
Thank god. Hurry up and buy it.
等等  如果之后我们碰到更好的怎么办
Wait. What if there's a better one later?
我们继续逛吧
Let's keep looking.
不不不  你就买这个
No, no, no! You are buying that.
你不可能找到更好的了
You're never gonna find anything better.
我就没找到更帅的救生员
I never found a hotter lifeguard, okay?
这个很完美  而且就在你面前
This is perfect, and it is right in front of you.
给  谢谢
Here. Thanks.
我很喜欢你的口音
I really love your accent.
谢谢
Wow. Thank you.
我要退掉这个
I would like to return this.
想什么呢
Penny for your thoughts?
咪咪
Boobs.
我也是
Me too!
我们到底怎么了
What's our problem?
那东西扑面而来的时候我就慌了
I freaked out when those things came at us.
我以为我能承受一个
I think I could've handled one,
但是它们一起来了
but they ganged up on me.
小伙子们
Hey, boys.
想不想参与一次
How would you like to participate
原住民徒步之旅
in an aboriginal walkabout?
不了  谢谢  你问问那些女孩吧
No, thanks. Why don't you ask those girls over there?
这次徒步只限男士参与
This walkabout's for men only.
相信我  我们算不上男士
Trust me -- we're not men.
看来你真的很需要这个经历
Sounds like you need this more than anyone.
快点  来吧
Quick -- come here.
真好  现在我们还化妆了
Perfect. Now we're wearing makeup.
你是在开玩笑吧
You have got to be kidding me.
我们可以走到丛林去吗
Okay, can we walk to the bush?
不行  调配中心会在1小时内派来新车
Nah. Dispatch is sending a cab in an hour.
-1小时  -搞什么
- An hour. - What?!
小卡  是我们活该
No, Cam, we deserve this.
我们抛弃了家庭  丢开了女儿
We deserted our family, we abandoned our daughter,
为了什么呢
and for what?
我们不仅是脑残粉
We're not just star you-know-what-ers.
而且还是大傻叉
We're you-know-what-holes!
你知道莉莉不在这儿你可以说脏话吧
You know Lily's not here, right?
我的天哪
Oh, my god.
[毒蛇  为活而骑行  为骑行而活]
镇定一点
Please be cool.
我一向很镇定
I'm always cool.
你们好
Hello!
鞋子不错啊
There's some pretty fancy shoes.
谢谢
Thank you...?
听我说  我们不想惹麻烦
So, listen, we don't want any trouble,
但是  我和我朋友
uh, but my -- my friend and I --
朋友  真的吗
"Friend"? Really?
是的
Yeah.
我们的车坏了
Our cab broke down,
我们要去找我们的女儿
and we are trying to get to our daughter --
我和我朋友共同的女儿
The daughter my friend and I have together.
这是不对的
Well, that ain't right.
爸爸们应该和女儿在一起
Daddies should be with their little girls.
说真的  这鞋子我能在哪买到
Seriously, where can I get a pair of them shoes?
他想要你的鞋  快给他
He wants your shoes. Give him your shoes.
什么  好吧
What? All right.
我不想要你的  我想要自己的
I don't want your shoes. I want to get me own.
他不想要你的鞋  快穿上
He doesn't want your shoes. Put your shoes on.
我就知道
I knew it!
歌洛莉亚  别生气
Gloria, don't be mad.
太迟了
Too late!
我知道这看起来很糟
I know this looks really bad,
但你必须要明白这是我
but you have to understand that this is my --
你的宝贝项目是吧  我知道
Your baby?! I know.
你们应该感到羞耻
And you should be ashamed of yourself!
你的丈夫正在进行精神之旅
You have a husband who is on a spiritual journey
还被袋鼠揍了一拳
and was punched by a kangaroo!
什么
What?!
歌洛莉亚
Gloria!
亲爱的  我刚听说
Honey, I just heard.
你怎么被袋鼠给打了呢
How did you get punched by a kangaroo?
很猛的一下
Really hard.
在脸上
In the face.
我很抱歉
Oh. I'm sorry.
天哪
Oh, boy.
我能帮你做点什么吗
Is there anything I can do?
你能别工作了陪我坐一下吗
Could you stop working and sit with me for a while?
-当然可以了  -谢谢
- Yes, of course I can. - Thank you.
好的  温柔点
Okay. Be -- be soft.
谢谢你  宝贝
Okay. Thank you. Aw, baby.
天哪  菲尔
Oh, my god. Phil.
亲爱的
Honey!
菲尔  一只野狗抢了我的电脑
Phil! A wild dog took my laptop!
1980年在澳洲曾有野狗叼走了一对夫妻的女婴
因女婴尸体从未找到  母亲曾被怀疑是凶手
看来它真的以为那是你的"宝贝"
Seems like a missed opportunity.
亲爱的  如果你想工作就直说吧
Honey, if you want to work, just say so.
不是  真的发生了  发生了
No! It happened! It just happened!
我什么也没看见
I didn't see anything.
我没看到你被袋鼠揍
I didn't see you get hit in the face by a kangaroo,
但我相信你了
but I believe you.
快点  帮我抢回来
Come on! Help me get it!
不  你自己去吧
No! You're on your own!
就像我独自旅行一样
Like I've been this whole trip!
我的天哪
For god's sakes!
歌洛莉亚  别走  听我解释
Gloria, stop! Let me explain!
好吧  但你最好别跟我解释说
Fine -- but the explanation better not be
这是个很重要的客户  而且你要赶进度
that this is an important account and you're on a deadline
什么什么什么的
and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah!
好吧  那我需要一分钟想一想
Oh. Well, I'm gonna need a minute to think.
我丢下乔  漂洋过海
I did not leave Joe, fly across the world,
不是为了来看你工作的
to see you spend all your time working!
你这样完全不是在度假
You're missing the whole vacation!
你不是第一个这么说我的妻子
Not the first wife to tell me that.
那你还要多少个妻子说才能听进去
So how many wives need to say it before you listen?
那是怎么回事
What's that?
我不会告诉你的
I'm not gonna tell you.
要是你之前在这里的话  你就知道了
If you were here, you would know what that is.
我也不知道那是怎么回事
I don't know what that was.
但我就是不想让他得意
But I was not going to give him the satisfaction.
该死
Damn it!
为什么  澳大利亚  为什么
Why, Australia?! Why?!
你好  伙计
Hey, mate.
怎么样
How's...it going?!
一切都还好吗
Everything okay here?
不太好
Not really.
恕我直言   你看起来有点狼狈
You don't mind me saying, you look a bit beaten up.
是的
Yeah.
我爱你的祖国
I love your country,
但是你的祖国并不爱我
but your country doesn't love me back.
澳大利亚讨厌我
Australia's rejected me.
你看到这里没有
You see this right here?
这是鳄鱼咬的
That's from a croc bite.
我后背上这个
This one here on my back --
是我在墨尔本被煤车撞的
I was hit by a tram in Melbourne.
这里这个...
This right here --
这个痣不正常
That's an irregular mole.
得去好好检查一下
Should probably get that checked out.
我要说的是  澳大利亚对游客是友善的
Point is -- Australia is nice to tourists,
但她对自己的人民却是苛刻的
but it's tough on its own people.
恭喜你  伙计
Congratulations, mate.
你是我们的一员
You're one of us.
你说的和我想的是一样的吗
Are you saying what I think you're saying?
我想是的
I think I am.
我是鳄鱼・邓菲
I'm Crocodile Dunphy?
这...和我说的还真不沾边儿
That's...not what I was saying at all.
那是笑翠鸟吗  天生看不见东西的
Is that a kookaburra, which are born blind, or --
妈妈
Mom?
你在这里啊
There you are.
爸  笔记本丢了
Dad, the laptop is gone.
我们得马上回酒店
We've got to get back to the hotel right now.
我还清楚记得里面的内容
It's still fresh in my mind.
我想我能再把内容凑齐
I think I can just piece it together --
克莱尔
Claire.
随它去吧
Let it go.
什么  不行
What? No!
我倾注了我的心血在里面
I-I poured my heart into this.
难道你不想气一气厄尔吗
And don't you want to stick it to Earl?
都无所谓
Doesn't matter.
和你的家人在一起吧
Go be with your family.
还记得你小时候吗
Remember when you were a kid?
我们全家出去旅行
We'd take the family trips?
然后我消失了好几天去工作
I'd disappear for days to work.
别和我一样
Don't be me.
我觉得我让你失望了
I feel like I'm letting you down.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我总算有点时间和我女儿一起度假了
I finally get to spend a little vacation time with my daughter.
是啊
Yeah.
那是什么
What is that?
莉莉  我们来了
Lily! We're here!
大爸二爸爱你
Daddies love you!
大爸二爸
Daddies!
我的天
Oh, my gosh!
这地方真漂亮
Oh, this place is beautiful!
那是我们的车  该走了
That's our bus! Time to go!
你是什么意思
What do you mean?
-这些人是谁  -这个人是谁
- Who are these guys? - Who's this guy?
亲爱的  真对不起
Honey, I am so sorry.
从现在开始  我只属于你
From now on, I am all yours.
我发誓  不管你想干什么都行
I promise -- whatever you want to do.
菲尔  我当初想的可不是这个
Phil, this is not what I had in mind.
你做得很好  亲爱的
You're doing great, honey.
什么叫做桥梁
What is a bridge?
它是一条纽带  一座支架
It's a connecter, a supporter,
而有时候  它象征着爱
and sometimes, it's a metaphor for the love --
-我的天  闭嘴  - 拜托
- Oh, my gosh! Stop!! - Come on!
你们好  我们在大堡礁
Hello, from the Great Barrier Reef!
简直棒极了
That was awesome!
爽
Yes!
澳洲航空
感谢您选择乘坐澳洲航空
Thank you for choosing to fly Qantas
由澳大利亚直飞洛杉矶的航班
on our nonstop flight from Australia to Los Angeles.
抛开家人坐在这里让我有些愧疚
I feel a little guilty sitting up here without the family.
-我不觉得  -我也是
- I don't. - Me, either.
你不觉得这样有些过分吗
Don't you think it's a little rude
他们竟然坐在前面
that they're sitting up there?
我永远都不会那么做
I would never do that.
你度完假马上就恢复紧张状态了
Boy, you tense up fast after a vacation.
我发誓我看到休・杰克曼在前面
I swear, that's Hugh Jackman up there.
我们登机时我看到他了
I saw him when we boarded.
我觉得那个不是他
I don't think it's him.
好吧  我要去查个清楚
Oh, well, I'm gonna go find out.
小卡  不要  小卡  拜托
Cam, no. Cam, come on.
让他去吧  要不我们谁都甭想睡
Let him go, or none of us will get any sleep.
伙计们  我过来打个招呼
Hey, guys. Just saying hi.
不好意思
'scuse me.
我觉得这个人不是头等舱的
I don't think he belongs up here.